

Muhammad Junaid Raza

LUMS, Opposite Sector U, DHA, Lahore, Pakistan Mobile: +923124145514; Email: mjunaidr3@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

A result-oriented and ambitious professional with strong interests in Security Operations, Python Development and DevOps currently working as a Software Engineer and open for an opportunity to further experience and knowledge in a challenging and encouraging work environment.

CURRENT ROLE

Ebryx (Pvt.) Ltd.

November 2018 - Present

Software Engineer

So far, I have worked with:

DevOps: Bitbucket/GitLab, Jenkins, Artifactory (Nexus OSS3), Building (PyInstaller)

Packaging (dpkg-deb), Ansible

Languages/Frameworks/Libraries: Python, Coffee Script, Shell Scripting, Selenium, Protractor,

RESTful API, pexpect, OpenCV2, Scikit-Learn, numpy, etc.

Development/Tracking systems and methodologies: GitHub, Testrail, JIRA, Confluence, Agile

Security Tools: Anyrun, Cuckoo Sandbox, Virustotal, NeutrinoAPI, hackerheart, Shodan,

RecordedFuture, WhoAPI, PEiD, Dependency Walker, PEView, ProcMon,

Process Explorer, RegShot, WireShark, burpsuite

Products and Tools: VSphere, Kubernetes, Postman, Anaconda

AWS: EC2, S3, VPC, IAM, Cognito, Rekognition, SNS/SQS

EDUCATION

Lahore University of Management Sciences

June 2014 - June 2018

BS (Electrical Engineering) - CGPA: 3.20

Relevant Courses: Network Security, Network Centric Computing, Computer Networks, Network Protocols and Performance, Machine Learning, Feedback Control Systems

EXPERIENCE

Lahore University of Management Sciences (LUMS)

Student Intern - Information Systems and Technology (IST) - Computing and Networking

July 2016 – June 2018

IST -Information Systems and Technology- is a department at LUMS that provides students with IT facilities ranging from IT-Labs to fast Internet connections. I decided to work at IST to get an exposure of professional environment and to be able to experience working alongside routine education.

Teaching Assistant – MGHSS – Education

Jan 2018 – May 2018

I have served as a teaching assistant at Mushtaq Gurmani School of Humanities and Social Sciences, managing and organizing tutorials and other grading instruments for a class of 40 students.

Education Ambassador - NOP Center - Education

June 2016 - July 2016

As an Education Ambassador, my task was to reach out to the young and bright yet financially poor students and inform them about scholarships. A lot of bright students in Pakistan have to stop their study at some point due to lack of financial resources and lack of knowledge of different kinds of scholarships offered across the country. I am still a part of this program and several students got selected from my area.

Coaching Session IT-Instructor - NOP Center - Education

June 2016 - July 2016

LUMS conducts a coaching session every year to familiarize A-Level/FSc students with University Life and conducts workshops on communication skill, IT-Introduction etc. Being an IT-Instructor, my task was to guide students about usage of IT facilities.

PROJECTS

Smartphone Apps Fingerprinting using Network Traffic

In this project we captured Network Traffic being MITM and analyzed the traffic using Machine Learning to guess the Smartphone Application being used. We built a temporal profile of every user connected to our internet service. This profile is helpful in network security forensics and for providing better services by ISP.

Decentralizing HVAC using IoT

HVAC systems use lots of power and a complete HVAC system has to be turned on even if only one person is sitting in the building. We brought an idea to replace HVAC by individual AC, Heater, Fan etc. in every office and

connecting them together using IoT. This helps control the devices remotely and a synchronous as well as asynchronous operation for whole-building, individual use respectively. This also reduces the monthly power usage by roughly 50%.

Weather Controlled Home Automation using Microcontroller and Xbee

Simple and low-cost implementation of home automation using Xbees along with sensors. The Xbee sends sensor data to Microcontroller which performs suitable actions after analyzing the data.

Obstacle Avoiding Robot Edge Avoiding Robot LFR-Line Following Robot

INTERESTS

DevOps
Cyber Security
Python Development
Machine Learning

CERTIFICATIONS/TRAININGS

Bash Shell Scripting from Udemy: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-54Z6JCEI/

AWS Developer - Building on AWS: https://courses.edx.org/certificates/34256fa2aad949e1b7bab6e64257cb0f

Medical First Responder (MFR), Emergency Medical Services (EMS) - LUMS

Emergency Medical Services is a student run department at LUMS that provides first aid services to students and faculty at campus. It is a volunteer work and the members work free of cost.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Fully Funded Undergraduate Program under LUMS NOP

2014-2018

LUMS provides scholarships to bright and needy students for study. This scholarship is based on the financial need and performance during tests conducted at LUMS. I was one of the 135 students selected out of around 6000 applications. This grant includes full fee waiver, free hostel facility and a living allowance.

Summer Research Program Grant

2017

Applied for and successfully received grant for 10 weeks Summer Research Program (SRP)

CHIEF MINISTER'S AWARD

2017

Received merit-based Laptop Award from Chief Minister Punjab

EXTRA CURRICULAR

Vice President, IEEE-LUMS
Convener, IEEE-LUMS
Director of Operations, EMS-LUMS
Director of Technicals, Dramaline-LUMS